#### Contact

joy.akhigbe@harrishealth.or

www.linkedin.com/in/joy-akhigbe-dnp-aprn-cmsrn-pccn-agacnp-bc-b9150682 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Nursing
Patient Education
Patient Safety

### Languages

English

Certifications
CMSN
PCCN
ANCC AGACNP

#### **Publications**

"I can't catch any Z's"

Great peace with understanding:
Understanding Palliative Care
Program Implementation, EvidenceBased Practice Project.

# Joy Akhigbe DNP APRN CMSRN PCCN AGACNP-BC

Hospitalist at Houston Methodist Hospital Houston, Texas Area

# Summary

Experienced Nurse Practitioner with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Nursing Education, Healthcare management, Nursing Simulations, Telemedicine, Emergency Medicine, FCCS, Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS), Critical Care, and Healthcare. Strong healthcare services professional with a Doctorate in Nursing Practice (DNP), Post Masters Adult Gerontology Acute Care Nurse Practitioner focused in Adult Gerontology Acute Care Nurse Practitioner from The University of Texas at El Paso.

# Experience

**Houston Methodist** 

4 years

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner October 2016 - Present (3 years 9 months)

Responsible for obtaining relevant health and medical history; Performing physical examination; Formulating diagnosis based on history and assessment findings and make referrals as required; Order diagnostic and therapeutic procedures; Evaluate and manage adult conditions utilizing practice guidelines and appropriate clinical judgment; Interpret laboratory and diagnostic studies; Offer counseling, education, discharge planning, and make referrals to meet patient needs; Document services, tests, and findings in medical record; Order blood and blood products; Pronounce death. Manage patients in the skilled nursing facility.

Hospitalist 2016 - Present (4 years) Houston, Texas Area

Chamberlain College of Nursing Visiting Professor

July 2014 - Present (6 years)

Responsible for the supervision and teaching of students during the clinical placement and high fidelity simulation portion of nursing courses for Chamberlain College of Nursing, and responsible for assisting the student to achieve clinical course objectives. Rotations taught include Fundamentals, Adult health I & II, Medical Surgical Nursing, Critical Care Nursing.

Harris Health System 19 years 2 months

Nurse Educator/ Clinical Resource Nurse October 2015 - October 2019 (4 years 1 month)

Responsible for assessing, planning, developing, implementing, and evaluating education activities, competency validation, clinical care, programs and initiatives. I provide leadership within the department including: quality improvement activities; support effective human resources management; and support resource accountability. Am responsible for facilitating an environment that cultivates exemplary patient care. As a member of the nursing leadership team, I establish a setting that supports professional nursing practice and empowers nurses to provide safe, effective, compassionate and efficient nursing care in collaboration with all health care disciplines. I support compliance with standards established by professional nursing organizations; national, state, and local regulatory agencies and institutional policies and procedures.

#### CLINICAL NURSE MANAGER

August 2013 - October 2015 (2 years 3 months)

Accountable for the shift operational management of the unit, and assisting the Director of Nursing (DON) with human resource, quality, and financial management. Oversees clinical operations and care delivery of the shift. Assists the DON with the implementation of plans and policies, and adherence to standards on the unit. Accountable for coaching unit-nursing personnel in implementing specific HCHD Nursing Professional Practice Model (NPPM) guided practices and facilitates achievement of targeted outcomes on assigned unit. Provide oversight to ensure area care delivery, quality management, and staff utilization patterns are congruent with NPPM framework. I facilitate actualization of shared governance and practice level advancement of area personnel. Responsible for facilitating an environment that supports professional nursing practice and empowers nurses to provide safe, effective, compassionate, and efficient nursing care in collaboration with all health care disciplines. Accountable for nursing practice that upholds

high standards of integrity and ethical behavior. Mentor others, role models professionalism, and participation in activities such as nursing organizations, and nursing research.

#### NURSE CLINICIAN

September 2000 - August 2013 (13 years)

Responsibilities include care of critically/acutely ill patients with multisystem disease processes with special focus on Cardiac Telemonitoring. Patients. Charging studies: making unit duty assignment, delegating and troubleshooting. Liaising with management, patients and families about patient care. Involved in creating QI projects, engaging in poster presentations, and a contributing member of COP in the unit.

Memorial Hermann Health System Consulting Nurse- Telemedicine November 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Responsible for triaging incoming calls from clients, assessing needs, giving appropriate clinical dispositions and facilitating referrals to primary providers, specialists, healthcare facilities and community resources. Educating clients when appropriate, regarding immediate care advice and preventive behaviors. I also participate in special projects, initiatives, and community services.

# ASTRODOME CHIROPRACTIC CLINIC CHIROPRACTIC ASSISTANT

January 1999 - September 2000 (1 year 9 months)

Responsibilities included assisting Chiropractor in caring for patients by getting patients ready for physical exams, modalities, and X-rays. Assisted in performing EKGs. Assisted in front office by verifying insurance, scheduling, referrals, reminders and data entering.

## Education

The University of Texas at El Paso
Post Masters Adult Gerontology Acute Care Nurse Practitioner, Adult
Gerontology Acute Care Nurse Practitioner

Prairie View A&M University Bachelor of Science, NURSING

Texas Woman's University

Post Bachelors, NURSING

The University of Texas at El Paso Master of Science (MS), Nursing Education

The University of Texas at El Paso Doctorate in Nursing Practice (DNP)